<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mesosphere on Vamp | Automation and Controls for Enterprise Devops</title>
    <link>https://vamp.io/platforms/mesosphere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mesosphere on Vamp | Automation and Controls for Enterprise Devops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vamp.io/platforms/mesosphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vamp Enterprise Edition Trial for DC/OS</title>
      <link>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v1.0.0/dcos-lifter-eval-spec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v1.0.0/dcos-lifter-eval-spec/</guid>
      <description>Vamp Enterprise for DC/OS
Thank you for your interest in Vamp Enterprise! To start using Vamp Enterprise you need to setup and configure some dependencies and environments. To make this really easy we&amp;rsquo;ve created Vamp Lifter, our setup and configuration tool. You can read more about Vamp components, including Lifter here.
 If you’re new to Vamp Enterprise Edition and you want a quick way to evaluate it, copy the Vamp Lifter application specification below and save it as file named lifter-standalone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DC/OS</title>
      <link>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v0.9.5/dcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v0.9.5/dcos/</guid>
      <description>There are different ways to install Vamp on DC.OS. On this page we start out with the most common setup, but if you are interested in doing a custom install or working with public and private nodes you should jump to that section.
 Universe package Manual install Custom install Public and private nodes  Universe package Vamp is available in the DC/OS Universe. Navigate to Universe in the DC/OS UI and search for Vamp and click &amp;ldquo;Install Package&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DC/OS Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v1.0.0/dcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v1.0.0/dcos/</guid>
      <description>This section describes how to quickly install Vamp 1.0 on DC/OS so you can evaluate it. The installation uses an installer built into the Vamp Lifter application to bootstrap a full Vamp installation.
After a successful installation, you will be able to login to Vamp EE as an admin user and deploy services.
Note!
Do not run this default installation in production! It does not include persistent storage and makes use of a Hashicorp Vault &amp;lsquo;dev&amp;rsquo; server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesos/Marathon</title>
      <link>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v0.9.5/mesos-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vamp.io/documentation/installation/v0.9.5/mesos-marathon/</guid>
      <description>Vamp can use the full power of Marathon running on either a DCOS cluster or custom Mesos cluster. You can use Vamp&amp;rsquo;s DSL, or you can pass native Marathon options by using a dialect in a blueprint.
Install The instructions included on the DC/OS installation page will also work with Mesos/Marathon.
Set Marathon as the Vamp container driver  Set up a DCOS cluster using Mesosphere&amp;rsquo;s assisted install on AWS (mesosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>